<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Race UP Team</title>
    <description>Race UP is the FSAE team of the University of Padova. Since 2006 we build one of the fastest racing car in FSAE competitions.</description>
    <link>raceup.it/en/</link>
    <atom:link href="raceup.it/en/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 09:21:30 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 09:21:30 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.5.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>RaceUP Team and Joanneum</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Joint test session held in Pista Azzurra (Jesolo VE) from 28/11 to 30/11 between the Race UP Team and Joanneum Racing Graz finished 2 days ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-meeting&quot;&gt;The meeting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The technical nature of the track coupled with low temperatures experienced during the test days put under great pressure both the handling and the reliability of the two cars involved: the MG 11.16 from Padua and the JR16 from Graz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;three-days-of-test-test-test&quot;&gt;Three days of test, test, test&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 3 test days have been extremely important as they enabled the two teams to acquire valuable information to be used in the next season. Just as important was the possibility to consolidate the already excellent relationship between the two teams through a mutual exchange of competencies and know-how.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;always-learning&quot;&gt;Always learning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Race UP Team’s fundamental objectives are growth and innovation, being able to cooperate with a Top Team such as Joanneum Racing Graz has been a precious and constructive opportunity!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;image featured&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/2016/12/03/image.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 18:35:15 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>raceup.it/en/2016/12/03/raceup-joanneum-together.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">raceup.it/en/2016/12/03/raceup-joanneum-together</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Seasonal summary</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Race UP Team Combustion Division, the project Formula SAE team at the University of Padua, is composed of thirty-five students from different departments of the university.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;determination-and-innovation&quot;&gt;Determination and innovation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The determination, the shared passion for improvement and innovation have allowed the team of students to achieve significant successes in the design, production and development of the car with an internal combustion engine. Thanks to the support of the University of Padua and of local and international companies, such as OZ Racing, and the commitment of the team, the team participated in the 2016 season of the Formula SAE: an international car race reserved for universities, which each year has committed about 500 universities around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;our-2016&quot;&gt;Our 2016&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More specifically, in 2016 the UP Race Team had the honor to participate in two events Significant progress with the car MG 16/11, presented in May in the department of Mechanical Engineering. The first of these is the twelfth edition of the Formula SAE Italy (Formula ATA), held in July at the Circuit Riccardo Paletti in Varano De ‘Melegari (Parma), where the fruit of the work of the Team took first place in the design and in Skid Pad and third place nell’Autocross, finishing in seventh place in the final of thirty-nine overall. In the second event, Formula Student Germany (FSG), held in August at the Hockenheimring circuit in Germany, the team it finished in fifteenth place on seventy-three in the overall standings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;results&quot;&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results represent for the team of students and their supporters a reason to continue the path undertaken with passion, with the intent to improve and achieve new goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;image featured&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/2016/10/23/image.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2016 19:35:15 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>raceup.it/en/2016/10/23/2016-in-review.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">raceup.it/en/2016/10/23/2016-in-review</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
